Juan Ignacio, MASCARENHAS.

Musician, Composer, Producer, and Sound Designer

I am a musician, composer, and sound designer with a strong passion for teaching and teamwork. Specializing in Jazz guitar, my skills range from performance and improvisation to composition and the development of orchestral arrangements.

iuanimasmusic@gmail.com

+54 9 2235603239

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juan-ignacio-mascarenhas-31b83729a/

https://jim-dev-portfolio.vercel.app/

🗣 Mar del Plata, Buenos Aires, Argentina

LANGUAGES: Native Spanish- English B2

TECHNICAL SKILLS

DAW: Ableton Live, Reaper, Adobe Audition, Pro Tools

Music notation software: Sibelius, Finale

Big Concepts: Performance. Improvisation. Stylistic Adaptability. Composition. Arrangements. Instrumentation. Musical Theory. Music Production. Recording and Recording Techniques. Mixing and Mastering. Sound Design.

SOFT SKILLS

Teamwork
Analytical thinking
Active learning
Problem-solving
Creativity and innovation
Adaptability

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

Music Composition - Master of Music (MM) **-** National Conservatory "Luis Gianneo" - 2017 - Dec. 2020

Jazz Guitar Music Professor - Bachelor of Arts (BA) – Faculty Institute of Art "Adolfo Abalos" - 2005-2011

CERTIFICATIONS

Oral Degree "The Art of Speaking" – "Mai Pistener" Communication Academy - Abr. 2022

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sound Designer 2021 - Present

"Soundscape Creation Worldwide"

- Specialized in: Ambient Sound Design, Foley Effects.
- Experience in field recording and sound synthesis.
- Additional skills in Audio Restoration and Noise Reduction.
- Participated in international sound design conferences and workshops.

Independent musician 2002 – Present

"Improvisación Colectiva en Mar del Plata"

- Main Musical Instrument: guitar.
- Musical Genre: jazz
- Secondary Musical Instruments: piano, bass, drums, sax, clarinet.
- 1000+ live music sessions
- 2 Albums edited with original music.
- Member of many musical ensembles: big band, small groups.
- Other music genres: Classical music, Latin music, Dub Techno music.
- Performed at multiple music concerts at various cities in Argentina, Germany, England, France and Spain.

Member of ICM: Non-profit organization 2010- Present

"Improvisación Colectiva en Mar del Plata"

Assemble of independent musicians with a common goal: to create spaces and musical activities with a sociocultural impact.

- Direction and coordination of live music cycles with 2000+ sessions.
- Direction and coordination of educational activities.
 Including masterclasses, workshops, individual and group classes
- 600+ weekly assemblies held since 2016.
- Record Label: 40+ edited albums.

Direction and coordination 2010– Present

"Festival Mar del Plata Jazz"

The Festival was born in 2010 as a result of the curiosity and creativity of a community of musicians seeking new spaces and bridges to export and import sounds, thoughts, experiences, and languages.

- Event completion for 12 consecutive years
- Call and selection of vendors and participants
- Optimization of grant funds
- Coordination of sponsors
- Selection, negotiation and management of venues
- Overall accounting for the event

OTHERS

Full-stack web developer (Node, TypeScript, React, Nextjs, Tailwind)